all right so welcome to boost holiday
Boost number three and we left off
having set up bash and Bash RC so we
have a nice pretty terminal now and a
pretty command line now we need a pretty
terminal and I I'm going to start by
saying I didn't know about West I mean
I'd heard of it for you know a while
maybe a month or two but I hadn't really
given it a try and up until last week I
was using elac and laak's got a lot of
problems and I I told you I wasn't going
to compare the too but there is a if you
go to my books list there is a why not
aakr Summary of why I dropped aity but
the most important reasons are uh
compatibility with control left bracket
for for escape over VNC um uh the use of
um uh you know just not supporting
emojis at all um in terms of like color
Pickers there's just a lot of reasons
not to but why should use westerm
instead so West term is the biggest
accomplishment in ter
Science and Tech that I have ever
experienced in 30 years it is absolutely
amazing um it uses ler configuration and
a bunch of a bunch of really amazing
reasons that you won't understand right
now I'm just going to ask you to trust
me on this one but it is great is there
going to be another terminal come up yes
in fact one of the subjects you're going
to get the most fight with people on the
internet over is the best terminal you
know what and I I debated for long and
hard why not just use the built-in
terminal so up to this point in the book
that we've been working through we have
used the default Terminals and they're
not horrible they work right they work
and but you know they have they have
limitations so let let me show you one
of the limitations of why we're using
Wester really quickly and one of the
limitations so I'm going to bring up the
old terminal here and I'm going to run
something called
sunrise and as you can see the colors is
pretty slow and the colors are janky
it's because the built-in uh terminal
for for Mac does not support millions of
colors it's also slower it's not GPU
accelerated that means the graphics
processing unit that runs games can be
used to to accelerate your terminal um
Windows terminal preview also has that
but it's not nearly as good as westerm
westerm was written R Us if you care
which means it's wicked wicked fast
there's one thing nobody will debate
about on Rust it is the fastest of all
the things out there other than c so you
know I'm not going to nobody's nobody
you know with any level of sanity would
ever argue that rust isn't the best
language to write a terminal in I
completely agree with that Locker
written in it as well as West term so a
modern terminal why do you need it well
if I I'm going to show you now I'm going
to do that exact same command that I
just did but um we're going to do it in
westerm uh and as you can see it's much
smoother it's got millions of colors and
it supports all kinds of things
including if you haven't already noticed
italics um and it's just it's just all
around better this the entire quality of
it it supports more uh fonts uh it
supports better uh you know more
granularity on the fonts the fonts just
look sharper I I know it's you just just
trust me westm is like overwhelmingly
better and for that reason we're going
to actually install it um and I pretty
much said all that in that first
paragraph So how do we install it um
well it's probably not going to be much
of a surprise in fact this step's going
to go very quickly because we already
wrote an installer for you so you can go
ahead and use that if you want now um
you're probably still using the old
terminal so let me pretend like I'm you
I'm going to pick pick up the old
terminal here and and you know I've got
the new you know the new bash whatever
I'm using a different color scheme but
you basic idea and so so where are we we
got to go into
two in my case do two you're probably
dot or dot files and there is so what
are we going to go into now now we're
going to go into the West term file
directory and you see we do an LS we see
a bunch of things in here and we have I
what what I want you to notice in here
is that we've actually downloaded for
you the aun monu nerd font this is an
open source font it's 100% free um so
nobody need worry and we bundled the
font into the dot files so that you
don't have to go get it it's already
there so um and we we put it into the
setup script so let's go look at the
setup script more or less setup set up
and you can see that it's there in order
to read this better though I'm going to
actually use uh view instead so this is
something new um I'm going to run view
instead of more setup I'm going to do
view setup now the thing for view setup
is view is actually using VI so I'm
going to use my arrow keys and I'm going
to navigate around in view right now uh
to look around now this is you don't
know this yet but you're actually using
the vi editor when you do this and
you're looking around why am I having to
do this because you can read it better
because there's color and there's syntax
highlighting it's better than less right
um so we're just we're just looking at
it and you can see that it's going to
copy this it's going to hard link a I
mean Sim link a file for the the
configuration file Lua is a language if
you know Roblox It Was Written in it um
and um so if if the operating system is
a Mac it means it's called Darwin which
is BSD Unix then it will install using
brew and it will install fond config um
if it's msys which is specifically git
bash or msus 2 but you don't know about
that yet um then it will install those
fonts for you will actually run
Powershell and it will go out and grab
the latest ubun monop fonts and install
them for you uh what else does it do it
it says again if you don't I'm just
giving you the overview so you can know
I'm not doing anything nefarious here so
here it's going to run this is going to
say if I already have loal share fonts
installed uh don't bother otherwise make
a directory and unzip the fonts in there
and then try to run them I'm not sure
that this actually works um I I think
this is the way it's supposed to work
but this actually this piece might still
need to be fixed so I might be changing
this but you don't have to worry because
if I do change it it would change it in
the dot files um uh it when in doubt if
the if the fonts don't work out and you
need to do the install I'm going to show
you an alternative way to get them to
work just in case this doesn't work for
you um but we why are we getting a bon
mono fonts because the font you're
looking at right now is a b mono it's
just easiest to read I've loved it for
years people are always asking me for
you can do whatever fonts you want the
default Western fonts are not
horrible but if you're going to use this
particular installer uh you're going to
want to do this and the reason for that
is because uh the fonts are uh built
into the configuration okay so um how do
you quit VI this is a big meme out on
the internet so we're we're actually NBI
how do we get out uh you can just do
shift ZZ and that will get you out okay
so two capital z's will take you out you
can do a lot of other ways to get out
but that's probably the easiest all
right so um now what let's go look at
something else let's look let's go we'll
use view to look at uh West term I'm
going to make a little title um
um wait um
give me a second I just got to see
see uh
document
[Music]
um uh move to view with
less uh for viewing because syntax
something I want to change in the book
actually so I'm just making a note here
to go change that in the
book all right
so um anyway so let's actually do this
let's do view view West term and you can
see westerm
now and again you can use yeah uh say so
zq does not yes I know ZZ is easier to
remember yeah and in that case the ZZ is
usually always what you want because you
want to say when you
exit uh oh boy somebody clipped my R
comment uh for dude I I have never said
anything bad about rust for for terminal
stuff I've always said it was positive
so here we go so I am using the arrow
keys I want everybody to see me using
the arrow keys here there's no shame in
using arrow keys you don't know how to
use VI yet so don't let anybody shame
you about using arrow
keys okay not when you're first starting
out when you're first starting out it's
okay again I did View and I'm using the
arrow keys to look around and what does
this thing do oh my gosh okay well first
of all it's l so you can see it's a
different thing it's is checking to see
okay what OS it is and okay that's cool
it's telling us what kind of shell oh
hey look there's where it decides to run
Bash that's cool okay then it says oh
hey if it's on a Mac use home Brin home
Homebrew bin
bash which is why we need to do the you
know the bash install in order to use
the right one for to get the right one
um and actually I think that's plenty
without actually changing it to be a
default shell I think it actually will
work just doing that by itself um detect
font so this actually we spent a lot of
time on this um bun mono is the way the
font gets detected on Windows it's
actually a bunch of mono nerd font on
that um we're still struggling a little
bit with the windows
fonts uh it's yeah so here we have um we
don't want to be prompted every time we
close when to set that up we use the
built-in Groove box material theme which
is the colors that I'm using right
now um we're going to the font I'm going
to set the font size to 26 so you're
looking at a font size that's like 37
right now so that it's easier to read
with my face on the screen um and then I
set I set the cursor colors a little bit
you know they're a little bit too bright
for my taste so I kind of turned them
down you don't know what CSS colors are
or anything like that yet but they that
is something that we can look at little
bit of padding um and this is I put this
here just for information so those of
you who want to see my values that's
that's what are that's what's going on
here uh this actually starts up my stuff
exactly where I want to and I don't have
any decorations I don't have um like the
the tabs at the top of of westerm and I
don't suggest doing this if you're on
Windows because on Windows there's no
t-s so having those tabs at the top in
fact t-o um because it's not available
on Windows um a lot of westerm users in
fact Sergeant Pepper another streamer um
said that he he has gotten used to the
multiple tabs and and using um that on
westerm on Windows when when you know
when there's no there's no t-mo you
don't know what t-mo is yet t-mo is a
way of having multiple windows inside of
the terminal um but but so so so t-u uh
being absent means you know the West
term is kind of nice so I don't
recommend turning any of that on but so
now that's a brief summary of what's in
the file all right so now having gone
through that again ZZ to quit if you
somebody mentioned in the chat you can
do zq if you don't want to
we're going to learn bi later okay and
you can pick from the five different
ways of exiting at that time right now
as a beginner it's just easier to
remember zezy top in fact I used to play
the zezy top legs
video probably not suitable for
work so when you want to remember how to
exit Vim just remember zezy top that's
the pneumonic device the legs video she
got legs she knows how to use them yeah
I'll answer that question in a bit all
so
so seriously if you have not seen his
easy top videos especially if you're a
13-year-old boy which is the target of
this
book go watch every zezy top video right
now you can thank me later you can thank
me
later oh then you come back and we'll
talk about who your favorite zzy to girl
is I know it's probably not appropriate
for me to suggest that
I did anyway I'm sorry I'm such a bad
santa anyway here we
go um what was I saying now all I can
think about is is the brunette in the
easy top video oh my gosh okay so anyway
I was 13 once I'm kind of 13 Going on 58
or
whatever so their favorite zy top girl
is the one with the beard lol
so why when you think of ZZ Top you're
going to think about ZZ and you're
remember how to get out of him see what
I did there see it's not a wizard thing
but it's pneumonic device sexy girl
equals pneumonic device get
it okay so have we looked at all the
files in here Rob yes we have we haven't
looked at setup yet let's look at that
one so we're going to view
setup we viewed setup okay I'm using the
the arrows I'm using the arrows okay I'm
going to tell you something right now if
you want to instead of using arrows you
can put your hand in the middle of the
keyboard so that your fingers are on JK
and L and you can push J for down and K
for up and you can do L to go over here
and you can do H to go over here why
don't you try it right now okay and you
tell me which one you want okay this is
we're using VI view the really great
thing about using view is you can't hurt
anything by using View
you're using V you don't know this yet
but you're using VI in readon mode so
even if you were to try to change
something you can't hurt it you can't
hurt it and a lot of beginners a lot of
veterans don't know about View and I'm
telling you right now it's very useful
because sometimes you just want to be
absolutely sure I am not going to ABS
you know accidentally fat finger
something in that file and by using view
instead of VI or Vim or whatever uh try
to change it yeah well they'd have to
know about that but you know yeah so so
yeah so like if I try to change it it it
just it won't it it it won't change it
right so I mean I'm not look don't
change it but you know I'm just trying
to that's why that's the difference
between V and VI um so we already looked
at this while but this is this is the
one that's doing all the setup
installation we looked at it already
again ZZ and I'm out of there all right
so now what I do this all the time just
cuz all right right so we're ready to
run it and so let's just do it you can
do/ setup and you can go ahead and and
run that and that will set up your your
westerm Lup okay now I'm not going to do
it for one reason only because I already
have a customized West term set
up but you know what to do here right
notice don't forget the dot slash and
make sure you're in the directory the
right directory and do do slash and run
that right now you're go ahead and run
that right now okay and when you run
that after you run that you can actually
test it and the way to test it is quite
simply uh and I'm going to actually turn
mine off so I'm going to turn um I'm
going turn off the question this thing
here so let's show you how to how to
start it
up um and let's actually let's go on
let's go on uh windows and try it okay
so let's let's do our Windows one so
this is a brand new one so let's go
ahead let's go oh wait I forgot to show
you something so you see I went CD do
dot that went up a level so I'm in do
files and I went CD do Dot and went
up uh so so right
um
uh set right with or
yes uh yeah okay so thank you for
that
uh so WQ is not a thing yeah WQ will
quit but don't do it it's it's too hard
to type why would you type that and not
just ZZ I'm telling you trust me do ZZ
it's way easier to type nobody ever
talks about it that's the way you should
do it if you want to learn the extra
ones that take five extra keystroke fine
I don't care I'm telling you ZZ is what
I teach people use ZZ it's easier to
remember it's faster the only other yeah
anyway so I don't do zq is too hard I do
WQ exclamation point but that we'll talk
about that later all right so we got to
run our thing here are we in the right
place I don't know what am I looking at
here okay I'm in the wrong place so CD
West term all right LS okay there's my
stuff I already know what's in there I
looked at it so now it's time to run
itq top does not have the same ringtone
uh we're learning how to code we're
working through the book it's in the
chat so click on the pin you can follow
along all right so as you can see uh I I
know that the windows West term setup
works because I've gone through this
extensively um this doesn't all the nerd
font there is some question about
whether the Mac one has a bug in it or
not but that will rest assured it'll be
fixed in the dot files template if you
want to follow that template you can go
click on it you can follow it on GitHub
if you want to see about notifications
or changes so here we go we got the nerd
font this is all installed so now now
what we can do so so actually right now
I can start it so I'm going to go exit
and now I'm going to go start I can you
know I can either click down here and
type it in uh or if you want to do the
hotkey you can push the windows key same
thing and then you can type Wes you just
have to type Wes you don't have to type
the whole thing usually just type Wes
enter and you're going to get the West
term and there's your happy pretty West
term now what I'm going to show you here
is that um that uh you know we
um well I don't know if you've even got
Wester insult yet do we forget that step
I'm not going through the book it's I'm
being bad I forgot to install westerm we
configure westerm but we didn't install
it whoopsie all right so let's actually
let's install it you guys don't know you
don't have it I'm I am bad streamer bad
streamer okay so back up it doesn't
matter if you did it out of order the
book is in the right order okay so let's
actually do it the right way so let's go
back to
bash let's pretend like I didn't do that
okay so so here is Bash again so let's
install westerm all right um and I
believe it's I don't remember what it is
let me show you a new this is bonus
command for the viewers at
home uh yeah you can't yeah yeah
yeah I'm trying to install it by yeah
you can't do less what you need to do
there is you need to go execute it I'm
going to show you I'm so sorry yeah so
so uh CD and what is it dot files
to all right so the way to uh to install
let's go into the
installer CD into
install
oopsie CD do/
install and wait where' it
go where am I I don't feel like I'm in
the right
place I feel like I'm in the wrong place
[Music]
here guys don't don't worry I'm I'm
messing things up here okay so don't do
you don't have to worry about this okay
let me let me get let me catch up all
right so accedian to install
and okay there we go so you see all
those installers in
there uh this EZ pretty often I don't
want to accidentally you setting ZZ to
know up anybody watching my stream right
now on Twitch disregard what that person
just said that is ridiculously stupid
idea uh I mean I I re respect your right
to do that if you want to but that's the
second stupidest thing I've ever heard
that's almost as stupid as like
remapping control C to escape
I read your whole
comment because you pretty often I
accident
end sorry for trying to be a true
Scotsman there are many ways to do it
yes yeah that that's an absolutely
horrible
idea that's one of the stupidest ideas
I've ever
heard okay fine um anyway
so this person has disabled ZZ on
purpose because they're afraid afraid of
accidentally pushing ZZ to to exit their
editor on accident first of all if you
accidentally did that who cares you're
you've exited vim and saved at the same
time so you just open it back up again
worst case scenario best case scenario
you don't fat finger ZZ all the time and
you actually use it as the fastest way
to exit Vim I I don't want to hear that
again okay here we go so yeah you do you
but I'm telling you that's dumb so
people all right we're installing
westerm because I forgot to tell you how
to do this so
view uh
westerm
and what do we got here we have a
thing that's running you can't really
see it very well because I'm running
bash but you can see that there's the
win and get if you feel more comfortable
you can just run wi get insall West term
too why don't we just do that you can
you know but you can just look at the
script if you run the script it will do
that it will do that for you but let's
just actually do it uh wi get install D-
ID it's not that hard right wi get um
oop sorry
Wes wes. Wes term and that'll go install
uh Western for you uh mine's been
already on there so it doesn't need it
and and now we can go back to the
previous step which is go ahead and
add um what ter by the way my strongest
agreement with what you said you know I
still love you you're probably a
wonderful person but that is a horrible
suggestion okay so anyway here we go um
Wes term so there we go we're going to
push enter and now we get West term all
right so let's let's talk about Western
for a second here while it's up now I
know it's not very I'm going to zoom in
so this is something that's super
important on Windows okay I I am not a
tabs person see how you can open up
multiple terminals by opening multiple
tabs right I am not I don't like tabs I
think they're a waste of time I would
rather use t-s and you'll learn about
that in terminal velocity but what I
want to tell you is that for um that for
when it comes to Windows since you don't
have Teamworks yet this is actually
extremely nice right this is extremely
nice and so in the absence of in the
absence of on Windows as an absolute
beginner and I mean that as an absolute
beginner you do not know about these
other things don't let people tell you
that you need to know about them now
it's going to distract you we've already
talked about it too much so just know
that this is going to give you the
ability to work on two things at once
you can open up another Tab and you can
have that running your tests and you can
have we're going to do that and the
other tab you can have that to be where
your code is running and another tab can
be your test cases so you can have three
files open at the same time without
having to get into the fancy ways to do
that using nbim or t-o you can just have
three tabs open for now and let me just
say that right now for now as soon as
somebody hears this this this kind of
speech like activates a certain type of
person because they're like oh my God I
can't believe you're teaching them that
that's like so such a waste of time and
blah blah blah blah blah and there's a
million other ways to do it and why are
they using multiple NE and pames why
aren't you teaching that first of all NE
and pames are a pain in the ass and you
shouldn't learn them you should learn
multiple t-u windows because you can cut
and paste from Shell and bimm processes
which you can't do with BM paines I
could go on I'm not going to I'm going
to stop right there I'm going to say
this for right now as an absolute
beginner just know that if you need a
new window you can use it using using
westerm okay you can use westerm and you
can open up in new window okay and and
that that's the only thing you need to
take away from that um you'll notice
that you're already using the bash
prompt you don't have to do anything
extra for that uh if for any reason you
are not looking at this you need to stop
and get this working because we're going
to proceed from this point and and and
that's it let's go back to the book and
review what we've done so far so we did
install West term we did it kind of out
of order we installed West term um and
you can do you can just install it like
I did or you can do it with the wind get
the way I did the way that by just
looking in the file it doesn't matter as
long as it gets on there and then and
then we did some other things right so
we did the setup here's the setup steps
uh here says command ID exe in the tab
that means you didn't run the config yet
so that means you didn't run the config
properly so yeah so if you if you just
installed Wiz term you need to make sure
to go run this if it if it still says
that please let me know okay so we had
somebody we had somebody say in the chat
that they're showing command. CMD as
their westerm prompt and that means that
they're not their their configuration
file is not being seen in the right
place so that means you need to CD into
westerm and do/ setup and then what that
will do is that will create those things
for you right it's going to put this
symbol it's actually in the case of
windows it's going to make a copy of the
West term. Lua file where it goes and
then the then then and then when you
open up westerm it should open up okay
uh uh put yes oh gosh um so so here we
go we're going to do let me just re
repeat this step so if if you're not
seeing uh bash. exe up here then
something is not right with westerm that
means it hasn't been configured um and
if that's the case let me just repeat
the steps one more time go back to your
git bash right CD into your dot files in
my case it's a weird name but CD into we
uh West
term and then LS and then you see the
setup file there and then SLS setup and
that will set up that'll
install uh your auntu mono fonts and it
will copy uh it will either Sim or copy
uh the West term Lua configuration file
so that the first time you run West term
uh it will be bash so let me repeat that
one more time so here we do we're going
to say Wes and now when we pull up Wes
term we have bash as our as as our
terminal that is the goal if if you
don't have that stop and work on this
until that's working for you because we
everything else is going to assume that
you have this terminal
running okay so let me go back to review
the the book again so uh I talked about
in the in the book here I do talk about
uh CD do dot do dot stands for Parent
Directory um and we we did we went ahead
and started up the termin terminal shows
you how to close it and restart it
showed you how to do that congrats you
got a brand new
terminal uh you got another command knot
found where it says command tab in the
okay did you do do
slash yes the custom wests action set
for the terminal can that us no please
don't give them anything like that elit
don't give them anything like that not
right now beginners don't need it stop
stop no we don't want cool we want
minimal we want the minimum
uh s it bashes no you don't people if
you install get bash properly then
everything should just
work I mean for my own stuff yes please
yes Le that would be great can I Rite
the commands from the script one by
one what script are you trying to
run first of all do you have bash on
your computer all right I'm talking
somebody through a problem here guys
maybe somebody else has the same problem
so we're going to we're going to cover
this all right so type this for me type
which which bash are you okay let's do
this okay make sure you have your bash
running let's let's like go break please
please do this exactly with me because I
really need to know because if you have
a problem I need to know about it so I
can fix it in the in the book all right
so in the westerm setup
scripts all right okay well let's let's
go
okay so we're we're back we're running
get bash now okay we're not we're not in
westerm we're in get bash okay and then
we're going to CD into the dot
files and we're going to CD
into uh
Western all right yeah that's
wrong that's totally wrong and that that
means you're not using G
bash because I mean look
I I don't know how you got that on your
system
but yeah did you did you do the bash
setup
already yeah you're using a different
bash
completely
so I don't I don't know how what
step okay that's good that's what it
should
be that's what I'm trying to tell you so
but here okay let's do
this it looks like you need to do your
bash setup we already did that step but
that s sounds like you missed that step
so let me let me go back on the system
and get rid of my get bash and we'll
pretend like we did everything from
scratch okay and we already did this in
a previous video but I'm going to do it
again all right so we're pretending here
we go so I'm going to take you from from
absolute scratch okay so we just
installed git bash okay just just
installed git bash and Bash enter get
bash is on the screen okay and um you
know it's
uh yeah I I think it's still actually
finding my my bashy I think it
is it is I thought I deleted it
but I me it's really hard for me to re
reset the system I need a VM so I can do
that but all right there we go all right
do you have this do you have this and
when you have this get let me know all
right go do you do you have it up here
ises it say
MW and does it say C users Rob do you
have
that because that's what we need to get
we need to get to the point where you
haven't done any bash setup
yet right
and and when you're doing this and you
do which bash it'll say user bin bash
okay and that's fine because that's the
bash that comes with get
bash but okay now CD we we did the clone
of the dot files so now we're CL we're
going into the yours is yours is
probably dots dot or do files whatever
yours is mine is do template so from
inside of here we're going to set up
bash again so we're going to go into
Bash
and we're going to do now that file is
showing as executable which it is
absolutely is not I do not know why that
is uh that should not be
executable I I have no idea why that is
that's kind of weird
actually that that file is not
executable in in GitHub I don't know why
that's listed as executable there it's
some broken thing on GitHub it
absolutely is not executable I don't
it's stupid
so why why would it do that this a
Windows stupidity anyway
so um okay so now we're going to do/
setup all right so that's going to
create the symbolic links and and now
rather than try to do exact bash DL
let's just
exit and then let's go back and type
bash again to get a new bash
shell um just to be absolutely sure
and now now I mean which bash should be
the same but you should see the terminal
should be different
now and it Windows is stupid but I'm
trying to it's it's still easier for
beginners than to force them to install
Linux right now I I swear by that uh
okay so now we've got it now let's CD in
template again or whatever yours is
files whatever now let's go into
westerm and uh well I mean we we already
installed westerm right so you already
went into install or however you want to
do this but we did westerm
install West
term uh to install West term and it's
going to install the fonts and
everything but it doesn't need it so
it's already there and now we're going
to configure West term so we're going to
proceed into West
term and we're going to run setup in
here and that should install the
symbolic links and create theb from
configuration
file and after that we can exit out of
bash and we can type West
term and we should have
bash
yeah uh sub light way get OS currently
one lags a
lot if you're going to reinstall a
different operating system and you have
that option then and you know about
Linux then install Linux but that's not
everyone it used to be when I taught
this stuff I required people to have
Linux installed but if you don't have
Linux then if you don't know what I'm
talking about then and we're not
covering that in in this every time we
tried to cover installing Linux it took
us like a month to get everybody up to
speed on Linux before we could even
write
code which a bunch of
mint if you're going to do a desktop do
a bunch of mint if you're a beginner the
end because it won't blow up on you and
it won't take you four months to master
before you can start writing the code
the reason everybody this is super
important the reason that we are not
screwing around with Linux disos and
pods and BMS right now is because we
want to get coding and every time we
screw around with that it takes us two
months to get everybody up to speed
before they can even write a first line
of code because all all the installing
and all the fighting about what Linux
dist to
use and it just gets crazy and and I'm
if I was dealing with you oneon-one I
would have you create a Linux Dro on
your laptop and I would hand guide you
about how to do that but because I'm not
with you one-on-one the best thing we
can do so we can get coding is set up
git bash on Windows and set up the
terminal and westerm on Mac the end if
you've installed Linux you're already
ahead that far but if you know how to
install Linux on your own or you know
how to use containers or VMS or by the
way the the then you know you can go
ahead and do that
sotu mint Linux Mint cinnamon
specifically that's my favorite Linux
drro for beginners because it's never
done anybody wrong it doesn't blow up
Papa West blew up mono blew up on
beginners I've had I've had beginners in
tears because they thought they broke
their computer because of mro I'm just
telling you my experience okay mintis m
is hands down the most stable Linux
Distribution on the planet is it the
newest no it's not it's the most stable
it's the most supported it's the most
stable it's the most mature it's the
most boring it's perfect for a beginner
if you're a beginner look if you're I'm
I'm I'm getting frustrated here because
how much time have we already lost on
this topic right we're we're 10 minutes
on what's wrong with
Windows all right so Ops out of the snap
packages yeah which I like I know I love
that I love that Min there's a reason
and I pick mint right yes my mom uses
mint yeah yeah people are going to I use
it AR people going to flex on you about
their Linux ask them what they've done
people who love the flex bath or Linux
dist and stuff don't do anything they
spend all their time configuring their
Dr they don't actually get anything done
I want to get stuff done I want to get
you coding I want to get you to start
writing code right now as fast as
possible if you want to spend time
customizing your terminal great we're
going to cover that in terminal velocity
next in another book okay and and I'm
trying really really really really hard
to go against my own impulses here which
is to have you just you know put a links
container on and be done with it and so
I have to admit Colonel before the
drivers Min has the Sur yeah we not even
talking about that m is absolutely go
davan is great
yes um yeah there look we could I mean
inev I brought I said Linux and now
everybody's got you know chiming in with
their opinion right now and as a
beginner just don't just don't just stay
with me okay get get bash installed okay
it'll be your first experience with bash
plus it integrates with your terminal
then get westerm working the way we've
got it working right now and then we're
going to a couple other things to do and
then we're going to be writing code
we're going to be writing code already
right and if you want to do all that
stuff just know that you can there's
nothing wrong with customizing your
terminal but it's going to stop you from
getting to the coding and I've already
spent way too much time talking about
this but I need to because this is on
the internet and the internet is full of
pardon my French that don't
care about you they want to flex they
want to show how awesome they are they
don't want to help
you and and I'm telling you right now I
am here to help you stick with the
simple stuff for now for now there's
going to be plenty of time to learn all
the other stuff later okay
so Dale I actually think you've already
screwed yourself over because you've
been listening to other people and you
they had either me or you put msis to or
you were trying to experiment well I was
experimenting and you were coming along
for the ride and now your system's kind
of screwed up because it's got like five
different things to soall so that's why
I spend so much time testing this stuff
for the first time for the first for the
easy person um yeah anyway so here we go
let's go next Okay so we've got we've
got the um we we should at this point
have westerm on if you don't have it on
and you are you're still having problems
and you screwed your computer up come
into the Discord come into our chat ask
us your questions and we'll try to help
you get it working okay get this working
get it working this is where having a
community really helps you got an entire
Community here uh on Sundays that's
available to help you you have a Discord
chat you can go to you have you know any
number of people you can go to you can
come into our IRC chat anytime you can
say hey I almost got it running but I
got this problem here and we can help
you debug your problem the chances are
if you're an absolute beginner you don't
have these problems because you know
you've done the steps in order and
something hasn't gotten out of out of
control um and you know learning how to
debug those problems and fix them
yourself is a skill that's good and
essential but that's it's also part of
operations but it's not required right
now right so we just want to get you to
the point where we can do the coding
okay so let's go back to here all right
so next we're going to install uh the
neoen meditor now this this this is
actually kind of a a thing for me this
is optional you do not need to install
the neim editor in order to participate
in anything in this book in fact you
already have an editor on your system
you can use right now but but it is so
easy to install
neovim that it's kind of worth doing so
let's do it okay what is neovim neovim
is the terminal based editor that's the
new Vim Vim is an older editor uh the
improved version of VI uh VI is the
visual mode of X and X is an improved
version of Ed which is the first te
which is the first text editor ever made
by human beings um so Bim is very
popular out there
okay people hear horror stories about
Vim it's actually not that hard as you
saw we've been using Vim to View files
but just pushing the arrows around and
and then you know escaping with or
getting out of it was EZ so it's it's
not as hard as people think people love
to make jokes about how hard it is to
get get out you know about ZZ now and
you can get out uh that is the standard
unic editor absolutely is and and X was
it was its pred with came after it s say
you know Ed came after it and then and
then VI is visual mode of Ed and Vim is
an improved version of VI and neovim is
an improved version of Vim so just so
you can see how that all plays out um
that's what's written up
here okay so uh yes uh and we still have
xrc and Ne I don't even know if you have
xrc is that still a thing interesting
okay so um so anyway it used to be you
had an XC change back into the dot files
directory hey Ben so okay so well let's
go let's go back to where we were let's
regroup I'm going to do this on Windows
uh because it's you know not messing
with my system here I uh Mac or Windows
it doesn't matter so in my case my files
template is called template yours might
be called something else so let's go
into um the Vim directory now inside the
Vim directory let's look around okay so
let's do view view and it.
Lua and you can see this is Lua language
you can see we've got a configured to
help you out uh I actually have the
screen key stuff in here so you can see
the keystrokes that you're pressing uh
on the screen by default uh you can
disable that pretty easily but I left
that in there uh a lot of people ask for
that and so I went ahead and left it in
in there you notice they're not on right
now because we're not running that but
uh so to get out of ZZ oops I'm doing a
macro oh no I can't get out there we go
so um so that's the first one of that um
you can you can view plug uh plug. Vim
plug. VM is a big big plug-in manager
that we're going to use for Vim there's
no reason to understand anything that's
in here just know that it's there uh the
vmrc is the core file and at this point
usually neim person will say why are you
using Bim RC why don't you just use it.
Lua the reason is so that you can use
your BM RC on any system that has viim
or neim it does not require you to have
neim which a lot of times you won't
have so that's why we use Vim instead of
everything in a knit. Lua but we have
the two files together and if you want
to see how those are set up I'm going to
show you if you don't if you just want
to trust me on this we're just going to
run the setup but I'm explaining it so
the setup is very simple it creates a
symbolic link to the VRC file creates
another it creates a directory for
autoloading the Vim plug-in manager uh
and then creates a Sim link to that and
then it creates an init.lua file which
if you're running neovim will be the
first thing to run and then that will
pull in or Source the vmrc file so that
if you have neovim it will use it and if
you don't have neovim it will just use
the vmrc and that is that actually
allows us to use something called
Progressive enhancement so we can detect
what's on your system and use what you
have and so let's get down with the
install so I'm going to type setup here
that creates the symbolic links and now
we can actually test this by doing the
same thing we just did um actually let's
just try let's do the same thing with VI
so now um actually let's do this first
let's exec b-l which gives us a new
login shell and then we can edit a file
here just for fun let's do VI setup and
you can see that you have the file there
now this is still using this is still
using a different one so I think we
still need to like log out and log back
in again but um let's
do yeah I don't let's
see yeah I don't know if it's going to
work what does our editor
say
huh I'm wondering why that didn't pull
up
uh I don't know let's try something here
let's exit and start up start up a new a
new West
[Music]
term
uh start up a new
one start up a new West
term should you could probably just do
another thing I'm just trying to figure
out
why
um oopsie control C to stop I need to do
control we'll see CD and a DOT
template or whatever your dot is all
right I'm going to read the read me
file yeah oh it's interesting I I must
not have turned on the um screen key by
default I must not have turned the
screen key on by default I don't see it
there so shift easz to get out or shift
easz is what you're getting out with
right now you can use the other stuff
later all right now we're ready to learn
Vim everybody so that's it we we are now
ready to learn
VI and let's actually recap a little bit
what we've
done um we we'll go back into
here and we are 47 minutes in so here
you can
see so we got this we got neim on there
it's
installed
um and what else we got um hey Don so
you got this you got install M CDN NE
m./ setup and then here's something new
you haven't seen so you see this Dash
the dash will take you back to what you
forgot you were at and I don't want
anybody to worry there's like a lot of
things to remember here and there's a
review section coming up that's got
every single new thing that we learned
line item so you can check yourself
let's go there now so confirm
installation you can do n rm- version
Vim Das version so um so this is
actually kind of interesting
um let's let's actually try this one
this is fun so let's do nm--
version and let's do vm--
version much different right all right
so let's actually go try that on on on
Windows as
well uh so Vim D-
version whoa look at that n
Vim Das Dash
[Music]
version it should you should have the
same color scheme if you did The
Bachelor C if you did the the West term
configuration
right if you did the West term
configuration did you skip that
step if you reopen West term you'll get
the new
configuration yep you should get the new
one if your westerm is being
seen yeah if for any reason your West
term Lua file isn't being
loaded it does have a bunch of them it
really
does so yeah if you want there is
something about Wim you can do um where
is
it I don't remember where it is in
westerm you can actually reload the
config but the if you're a beginner just
close it and restart
it so if you want to use a different
color skin that's fine but I'm telling
you right now everything in this book is
designed for GU boox material and I
can't promise you that it's not going to
look bad in your stuff every single
theme in every app is designed to use
grp box material if you want to start
configuring with a different material
thing that's fine but just please wait
because you might end up making it so
something doesn't appear as well and you
might you know end up wasting time on
that so I I'm not opposed to you doing
it I just
yeah uh to not memory leak I usually
don't trust reading the config to not
memory leak
yeah uh I have the defa com scenes for
now okay but are you are you do you have
here okay somebody's using a default
color theme the re the only reason that
would be is if you did not run the
config right you did not run setup in
the config directory so did you do this
did you go into the West term directory
and did you run dots did you run
setup did you do this part
where it's writing all the bites and
stuff and then it's doing the
thing inside of the
westerm okay now you have to restart so
you go out and then start up a new
westerm I I I want to stay with you on
this because maybe you found a bug so in
our
config so you should be getting the new
colors I wonder I wonder if there's uh a
reason that it wouldn't be built
in it's still the default
colors did that not change
it no I don't I've been using West turn
we covered that
already yeah you have to go back in the
video and watch it I cover a whole thing
about why I dropped aity I wrote a whole
thing in the fq on the books link if you
click on the code books link and you go
back to just books and click on uh shut
the pack up you can go read why I
dropped a
lacer if you want to know why um lacer
did me wrong for the last
time it's a lot slower too in Western
anyway if if you're still having trouble
getting the configuration just to show
up you know let us let us know otherwise
I'm going to
proceed um so again this these steps in
the book are designed to go sequentially
if you miss a step like you didn't saw
West term or your Bachelor SE is
different
uh or something like that you know then
that that might be a problem uh C Matrix
in the
background is a screen saver C Matrix no
it's
Neo but it's not there right now so yeah
uh way better actually yeah you're
talking about
this this is
Neo yeah it's it don't you have to
compile it
so um anyway that's all stuff that's
terminal velocity stuff that's not in
the book
yeah Neo it's in my DOT files which you
know RX Rob on get you can go find that
okay so next what are we doing now we're
going to do we did we did we did enim we
did both of the versions now we know we
got those different
versions uh neam is it talks about the
difference between them it's a lot of
history just know that no other editor
can claim that line of authority it's
true try this for fun VI version notice
that is the same okay so if if you've
done your Bachelor C rate then VI will
be neim and let me show you what I mean
by that vi-- version and the reason for
that is something called Progressive
enhancement um which says that VI is
Alias to editor and editor is set I'm
going to actually show you you don't
need to care about this but what it does
is the Basher C that you installed
actually will set up this Progressive
enhancement for Vi and what it says this
here is it says if I have Vim then set
my Editor to V to to set the editor to
to to VM to VI which in my case is is I
could have put that to be viim but it's
VI in that case if it's nbim then set
the editor to um if I have Bim that
should have been Vim actually and then
if it's nbim set the Ed to
Vim right fact I need to make I think
that might be a book
so what have to it should be Bim but the
main reason it's working is because nbim
gets detected and then it sets the
editor to nbim okay so that's why when
you say you know type VI when you type
VI whatever it does it in VI okay and it
uses the editor that you have um so
let's move on from that let's actually
start using it and learn how to use it
so activate your plugins okay so this is
always a really tough one um and
um this command actually activates the
plugins from the command line but you
can also do this inside of the program
so let's actually attempt it both ways
okay I'm going to show you how to do it
both ways um just so you know whenever
you do a plus here and a plus QA what
that says is it says run VI do all the
things and then exit right and so we're
using that as a way to to in to get our
plugins ready
right so so let me show you what that
does I let's do it on Windows I mean on
Mac ver so VI uh and this is the kind of
thing where you can do it over and over
and it's not going to hurt anything okay
so even if you have already done it once
oops I'm wrong system here even if
you've already done it once um you can
do it again VI Plus plugin plug is it
plugin install yeah plugin install not
plug-in install did I did I have that
right yeah and then plus QA and that
just says immediately exit so and then
we're going to execute that and you see
it ran so fast we didn't even see what
it did right now you can do the same
thing from in within bi it's just a
little harder if you want to try that
it's not in the book but I'm going to
show you how so you you VI it just
started up on anything and then it's a
blank page and then you type colon plug
and if you want to you can type Tab and
then tab tab tab to the install and then
you can type plug install enter and it
will do the same thing but in this case
you get to see what it did so it
actually went out and got all the
plugins from the internet and it
downloaded them okay and and now you can
quit and quitting is the same way
ZZ uh will get you out of there okay so
ZZ gets you out so there now if you if
you want to at this time you can also
install the go binaries now you can
actually wait to install the go binaries
until you do the go thing this is going
to take you quite a while and and let me
show you what I mean it it has to
download and compile like 12 different
programs in order for to run it'll
probably take you about 5 or 10 minutes
for it to finish um but so I'm not going
to do that Command right now but it's
exactly the same in every other way as
plugin install it's just go install
binaries and um again you can run it
from the command line and sit around and
wait for it uh or you can wait for that
command and do it later on if you want
uh I don't need to do because I've
already done it if you don't have that
uh later just to give you a preview um
you're not going to get this kind of
stuff right so like if I screw something
up you see uh
oops I'm trying to break something here
all right so you see how the errors pop
up and everything and all that stuff
that none of that stuff is going to
happen unless you have that set up
correctly so you're going to need those
binaries for that and um you see this
how this gets automatically installed
watch what happens when I save it um
oops uh okay so when I automatically
took that out you can see that it
automatically removed the input import
statement if I had if I had if I didn't
have these plugins for any other reason
that would be the major reason one of
the most annoying things about go that
we'll get into is removing and adding
and managing everything in this little
import section and the thing is really
cool about this is that when you save I
don't know what's going on I've got
um I have something going on uh I must I
must have broken something I don't I
have to go figure it out what I broke
error detect about processing buff PR
aut commands buffer equals
one something about my install has
caused it to break I don't I don't know
what so I I'm probably broke it doing
all the install with you today um I've
been I mean I did 12 hours ago program
yesterday so I have no idea what that's
about it's definitely new though um
anyway so so that's what you
do and okay so now is learn the B Basics
and that is a good place for us to end
so this has been an
hourlong uh session uh by the end of it
you should have every tool installed
that you need um to to have so we
installed the westerm terminal we
installed
neim uh and we tried to resolve any
problems we in the last session we
installed bash and adop
we are now ready to learn vim and so the
next session we're going to learn the
Vim Basics so stay tuned for that come
on back and check it out with us um and
then we're going to go ahead and create
a cookbook and we'll start practicing
our VM we're very close to writing some
code but let's learn Vim in the next one
I know it's been frustrating if you have
any help you need some help come on in
find us in the Discord find us in the
chat um and and ask your questions um
otherwise um and yeah if you if you guys
have problems uh please let us know
because I'm not ruling out that the
problems are related to our
configuration for the beginners um
because we we do tweak that quite a bit
so please let us know if you have a
problem please don't be shy um if if you
have a problem because it it could very
well be that the problem is is is on our
side too so please don't be shy about
the problem and um when we come back to
the next video be about viim see you in
a bit